<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://china4china.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://china4china.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-03-04T22:41:16-08:00</updated><id>http://china4china.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">China4China.com</title><subtitle>A blog dedicated to sharing interesting things in China. If you are curious about China, please feel free to contact me at any time. I am very happy to answer for you.</subtitle><author><name>FireRick</name></author><entry><title type="html">How many hours a week do Chinese people work?</title><link href="http://china4china.com/daily_life/2019/03/03/work-hours-of-Chinese-people.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How many hours a week do Chinese people work?" /><published>2019-03-03T06:35:18-08:00</published><updated>2019-03-03T06:35:18-08:00</updated><id>http://china4china.com/daily_life/2019/03/03/work-hours-of-Chinese-people</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://china4china.com/daily_life/2019/03/03/work-hours-of-Chinese-people.html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;questions&quot;&gt;Questions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;What are the statutory holidays in China?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;How many days do we work a week in China?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Is OT(overtime) serious?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally speaking, in China, most people start work between 8 and 9 o’clock and leave work between 17 and 18 o’clock. At noon, there is usually 1 to 2 hours of rest for meals and lunch breaks. That is to say, most people work 6 to 9 hours a day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the week, you need to work for 5 days, and the rest of the two days to rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, there are also statutory holidays that do not require work. There are 7 holidays listed below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table class=&quot;table table-hover&quot;&gt;&lt;caption&gt;statutory holidays&lt;/caption&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;New Year&amp;#39;s Day&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;January 1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;one day off&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Spring Festival&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1st day in the 1st lunar month&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;three days off&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Qingming Festival&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;around April 5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;one day off&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Labor Day&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;May 1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;one day off&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;The Dragon Boat Festival&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;5th day in the 5th lunar month&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;one day off&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Mid-Autunm Festival&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;15th day in the 8th lunar month&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;one day off&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;National Day&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;November 1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;three days off&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But not everyone is so lucky. At present, there are a large number of people in China who are suffering from overtime, especially young people living in big cities, because the prices of housing in big cities are very high. Most people may not be able to buy 2 square meters of income for a whole year. So they are under tremendous economic pressure, and they don’t have much bargaining chip on their work, because they need a steady income to repay the monthly housing loan. In addition to working overtime on weekday nights, weekends often have no time to rest, and sometimes even need to work until the early morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most technology companies have the most serious overtime, such as software companies, mobile phone manufacturers, Internet companies and so on. Huawei, a well-known company, has even turned overtime into a culture, but its rationality has been controversial. Everyone has their own views.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>FireRick</name></author><summary type="html">Questions What are the statutory holidays in China? How many days do we work a week in China? Is OT(overtime) serious?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Can I use google in China?</title><link href="http://china4china.com/daily_life/2019/03/03/can-i-use-google-in-china.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Can I use google in China?" /><published>2019-03-03T06:30:18-08:00</published><updated>2019-03-03T06:30:18-08:00</updated><id>http://china4china.com/daily_life/2019/03/03/can-i-use-google-in-china</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://china4china.com/daily_life/2019/03/03/can-i-use-google-in-china.html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;questions&quot;&gt;Questions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;What search engine does the Chinese use?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Can I use facebook in China?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;What social software does the Chinese use?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t been to China, you probably won’t know that in mainland China, you can’t connect to Google’s servers, so you won’t be able to use Google’s various services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to Google, well-known websites such as facebook, twitter, and youtube are also unable to connect. This is mainly because mainland China’s network service providers have filtered requests for these web servers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, there is a search engine developed by a local company in China, called Baidu. This is a search engine that focuses on Chinese search, so there is basically no one to use except Chinese.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like search engines, people in mainland China can only choose to use local social software due to network restrictions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than a decade ago, many people used Microsoft’s MSN. By now, most people are already using local social software. These softwares are mainly WeChat, QQ, Weibo and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on China’s huge population, these companies have become very large and are among the top Internet companies in the world.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>FireRick</name></author><summary type="html">Questions What search engine does the Chinese use? Can I use facebook in China? What social software does the Chinese use?</summary></entry></feed>